Guide to the Anne Ramsay Somers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1972-1989; Accession 1989-M-082; 6 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - Writings and Project Files
    - Princeton Borough-Princeton Township, Joint Commission on Aging, 1987 October 17 (Box 6)
    - American Public Health Association, New Orleans, "Should Nursing Homes be Required to have Institutional Ethics Committees?", 1987 October 20 (Box 6)
    - Boettner Research Institute Invitational Research symposium, Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, 1987 October 22-23 (Box 6)
    - Anna Alexander Greenwall Geriatric Center Dedication Ceremony, Monmouth Medical Center, New Jersey, 1987 October 24 (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Community Care, Inc., 1987 October 28 (Box 6)
    - Monroe County Long Term Care Program, Inc., East Rochester, 1987 October 30 (Box 6)
    - Princeton Theological Seminary workshop on medical ethics, 1987 November 2 (Box 6)
    - Pennswood Village, Pennsylvania, 1987 November 12 (Box 6)
    - Bioethics Committee of Overlook Hospital, New Jersey, 1987 November 17 (Box 6)
    - Economics and Ethics for Disease Prevention, seminar at Robert Wood Johnson Academic Health Science Center, 1987 November 20 (Box 6)
    - New Jersey Task Force on Catastrophic and Long-Term Health Care, Trenton, 1987 November 24 (Box 6)
    - McGinnis, 1987 December 2 (Box 6)
    - Channel 13, McNeil-Lehrer Newshour, 1987 December 17 (Box 6)
    - The New York Times, "Private Behavior, Public Responsibility," by James Reston and "News from Bethlehem," by Flora Lewis, 1987 December 25 (Box 6)
    - Health Policy, "Aging in the 21st Century: projections, personal preferences, public policies: A Consumer View", 1988 February (Box 6)
- Additional Material, 1948-2006; Accession 2007-M-098
  Accession comprises presentations, writings, and topical files relating to gerontology, long-term care, medical challenges facing the elderly, the Social Security and Medicare programs, and health care policy-making at the state and national levels.
  - Presentations and talks
    - American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging, 1995 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Princeton, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Area Agency on Aging, Bucks County, 1999 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Carolina Meadows, 1995 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Williamson Institute, Virginia Commonwealth University Ethics Conference, 1994 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arbor Glen Retirement Community, 1997 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - National Academy of Social Insurance, 1998 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Medford Leas Retirement Community Health Care Forum, 1996 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging, 1994 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - University of Kansas Nursing Homes Conference, 1990 fall (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ralston-Penn Center, 1995 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia Presbytery Homes and Services for the Aging, 1999 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Veterans Affairs Senior Management Conference, 1990 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ralston-Penn Center, 1990 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Friends Committee on Aging, 1990 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - University of Pennsylvania: Geriatrics Interdisciplinary Group Conference, 1989 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Advisory Council on Education for Health, 1989 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Foulkeways Residents Association (Gwynedd, PA), 1996 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - National Council on Aging: Mann Award, 1996 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Senior Action Group Endeavor, 1995 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Aging is Living Conference, 1991 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - White Horse Village, 1994 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Chandler Hall Auxiliary, 1995 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Pennswood Managed Care Conference, 1995 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Philadelphia Presbytery Homes and Services for the Aging: Managing Managed Care, 1996 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Pennsylvania Rural Health, 1996 June (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging: Continuing Care Retirement Community Lifestyle, 1996 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Temple University Association for Retired Professionals, 1996 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - National Conference on Home Care Quality, 1962-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Foxdale Village, 1994 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Regional Hearing for Year 2000 Health Objectives, 1988 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - American College of Physicians, 1988 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Third Health Issues Conference, 1993 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - New Jersey Public Health Association: Challenge of Long-term Care, 1989 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - National Health Council, 1988 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Symposium of Sensory Change and Aging, 1988 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Association of Academic Health Centers, 1988 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Blue Cross of Western Pennsylvania Conference on "Government Programs, Perspective '90,", 1989 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Health Care Hall of Fame, 1993 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Department on Human Health Services Colloquium, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Zubrow Award (Pennsylvania Hospital) lecture, "Rethinking long-term care: a personal journey,", 1994 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Pennswood presentation on post-election thoughts on health care delivery, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - U.S. Senate hearing testimony on long-term care, 1984 February (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Workshop on long-term care for the elderly, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Northwest Area Health Education Center Conference, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Frontiers in Successful Aging conference, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - National Institute on Aging and the Beverly Foundation conference, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Community Council of Greater New York presentation on rethinking Medicare, 1984 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - University of Connecticut Health Center Symposium on Geriatrics, 1984 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - New Jersey Association of Nonprofit Homes for the Aging annual meeting, 1984 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - New York University Medical Center Conference on Current Trends in Geriatric Rehabilitation and Long-term Care, 1984 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - American Nursing Resources seminar on The Aging Population, 1984 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Hospital Planning Association of Allegheny County (Pittsburgh, PA) Institute, 1986 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Pennswood Village presentation on successful aging, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - University of Pennsylvania, Divison of General Internal Medicine research conference, 1991 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Canadian College of Health Services Executives conference, 1984 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Hearing on Home Care, Borough of Manhattan, New York City, 1984 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Institute of Medicine annual meeting on "Protecting and advancing health in an era of contrained resources,", 1984 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry symposium, 1986 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - East Orange General Hospital Board of Trustees, 1986 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Florida International University, Southeast Florida Center on Aging, 1986 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - University of California Academic Geriatric Resource Program conference, 1986 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Center for Corporate Public Involvement, Advisory Council on Education for Health, 1986 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Pittsburgh Health Education Center, 1985 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Wellness Program at Waverly Heights (Gladwyne, PA), 1994 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging annual meeting, 1994 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Summaries of Anne Somers' professional activities, 1966-1993 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Ohio Department of Aging, Sixth Annual Multi-disciplinary Institute on Aging, 1985 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - National Academy of Sciences Institute of Medicine, Committee on an Aging Society, 1983 July (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Home Health Agency Assembly of New Jersey conference, 1986 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Academy of Medicine of New Jersey, Symposium on Geriatrics, 1984 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - University of Medicine and Dentistry of New Jersey, Rutgers Medical School, Resident Lecture Series on Socio-Economics of Health Care, 1985 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Association of American Medical Colleges, Northeast Group on Student Affairs, 1986 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - International Association of Gerontology, XIII Congress, 1985 July 13 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Florida International University, Southeast Florida Center on Aging, Symposium Celebrating 50th Anniversary of the Social Security Act, 1985 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Pennsylvania Public Health Association annual meeting, 1986 October 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - New Jersey Task Force on Catastrophic and Long-Term Health Care, public hearing testimony, 1987 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Public Health Conference on Records and Statistics, Data for an Aging Population, 1987 July 15 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - National Leadership Commission on Health Care, Workshop on Financing Long-Term Care for the Elderly, 1988 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Writings
    - Letter to Editor: The New York Times, 1999 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Letter to Editor: New England Journal of Medicine, 1999 September 23 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Book review of Parting Company in New England Journal of Medicine, 2000 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Nursing Homes and Ethics Committees, 1989 January (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - "Ten Principles or Guidelines for National Health Care Reform in the U.S." Note: may be unpublished, 1993 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Letter to Editor: Journal of Long Term Home Health Care, 1995 October (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Memorandum to Congressman James C. Greenwood, 1995 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - "Priorities for Reform" in Aging Network News, 1996 June (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - "Challenges to Elderly Facing the Twenty-first Century" in Aging Network News, 1996 May (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - "Continuing Care Retirement Community" in Encyclopedia on Aging, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - "Rethinking Long-Term Care" in Journal of Long-Term Home Health Care, 1995 Winter (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Letter to Editor: Princeton Town Topics, 1994 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Letter to Editor: The New York Times, 1994 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Health care debate, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - "One Hybrid Approach Toward Long Term Care" in The Internist, 1990 May (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - "How to Control Diabetes and Its Costs" in Business and Health, 1990 February (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - "Is Comprehensive Care for the Elderly Fiscally Viable?" in Care for the Elderly: Reshaping Health Policy, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Long Term Care, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Long Term Care Proposals, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Letter to Editor: The New York Times, 1995 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - "Long Term Care for the Elderly": Pride Institute Journal, 1992 April (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Book review of Changing Perceptions of Aging and the Aged in Journal of Case Management, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - "Senior to Congress" in AHA News, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Chapter XVII: "Politics of Health" from unknown book, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - "Centrist, holistic approach needed for Medicare reform" in Bucks County Courier Times, 1995 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - "Steering toward a proper course" in Business and Health, 1988 August (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - "Rejuvenate elderly health care policies" in The Internist, 1988 May (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Rehabilitation preface, 1988 April (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - "Distinctive role of the hospital" in Role of Hospitals in Geriatric Care, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - "Long-term care policy: a vital concept in need of better understanding and a new strategy" in The Internist, 1989 July (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - "Long-term care: the need for, and limits of, an effective Federal role" in Annals of Internal Medicine, 1988 August (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - "Conceptual yardstick for evaluating health care reform proposals,", 1993 July (Box 2, Folder 111 - 112)
    - Aging in the 21st century: Projections, personal preferences, public policies - a consumer view in Health Policy, 1988 September (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - "Lifecare: A viable option for long-term care for the elderly" in Journal for American Geriatrics Society, 1993 February (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Letter to Editor: Health Affairs, 1993 June (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - "Diminished expectations?" in Aging Network News, 1995 August (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - "Long term care for the elderly: Major developments of the last ten years" in Pride Institute Journal, 1992 April (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - "Toward a new national policy on aging: Setting treatment limits or promoting health and productivity?" in Health Management Quarterly, 1988 March (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - "Preventive health services for the elderly: The growing consensus" in Health Promotion and Disease Prevention in the Elderly, 1988 June (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Letter to Editor: The New York Times, 1995 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - "Why not try preventing illness as a way of controlling Medicare costs?" in The New England Journal of Medicine, 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - "Toward a comprehensive reform of U.S. health care" in Trends in Health Care, Law & Ethics, 1992 May (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - "Long-term care: Reducing the risk to insurable proportions" in Frontiers of Health Services Management, 1988 November (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - "Continuting Care Retirement Community (CCRC): One viable option for long-term care insurance" in DRG Monitor, 1988 December (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Letter to Editor: The New York Times, 1989 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - "Continuing Care: a concept and a name whose time has come,", 1993 April (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - "Unfolding Future" in Medicine and the Hospitals, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - "Four 'orphan' areas in current medical education" in Family Medicine, 1987 Mar/April (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - "Lifetime health-monitoring approach" in New England Journal of Medicine, 1977 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - "Major issues in national health insurance" in Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly, 1972 April (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Newspaper articles, 1984-1993 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - "Revising the balance of health benefits and fixed physicians' fees" in Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, 1984 Jan/February (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - "Who's in charge here? -- or Alice searches for a king in Mediland" in Journal of Interprofessional Care, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - "Insurance for long-term care" in New England Journal of Medicine, 1987 July 2 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - "Nursing homes and ethics committees" in New Jersey Medicine, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - "Long-term care: the need for, and limits of, an effective Federal role" in Annals of Internal Medicine, 1989 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - "Long-term care policy" in The Internist: Health Policy in Practice, 1989 July (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - "The 'geriatric imperative' and growing economic constraints" in The Journal of Medical Education, 1980 February (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - "Moderating the rise in health-care costs" in The New England Journal of Medicine, 1982 October 7 (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - "Health services in the United States: Groping toward a 'system'?" in Pannenborg et al., Reorienting Health Services: Application of a Systems Approach, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - "Why not try preventing illness as a way of controlling Medicare costs?" in New England Journal of Medicine, 1984 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - "Individual behavior and health" in Maxcy-Rosenau, Public Health & Preventive Medicine, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - "Is comprehensive care for the elderly fiscally viable?," chapter in book by Eisdorfer, circa 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - The B.M.A. Strike - the doctors' dilemma, National Health Service (U.K.), 1957 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - "The rationalization of health services: a universal priority,", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Responses to articles and editorials by others on health care issues, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Bucks County (PA) Courier-Times piece on health care reformers, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - "'Lifecare': a viable option for long-term care for the elderly" in Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - "Long term care: hungry stepchild of the U.S. health care system" in The Internist, 1986 September (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - "Health needs of the elderly," American Journal of Ophthalmology, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - "Health care and the political system" in, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - "Preventive health services for the elderly: the growing consensus" in Lipschitz and Chernoff, eds., Nutrition and Aging: Health Promotion and Disease Prevention in the Elderly, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - New York Times letter to the editor, 1985-1994 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - "Good and bad news of the long-term care crisis" in Perspective on Aging, 1986 November-December (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - "The case for prevention: how strong is it?" in Hastings Center Report, 1987 April (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - "NJ hospitals react to the 'geriatric imperative'" in Hospitals, 1986 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - "The changing demand for health services: a historical perspective and some thoughts for the future" in Inquiry, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - "Is prevention better than cure? You had better believe it" in Business and Health, 1987 March (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Topical
    - Medicare issue for LWV, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Somers, Sara, 1999 October (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Stone, Robyn, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Long term care memorial general, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - White House Conference on Aging, 1995 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 163 - 164)
    - Meeting with Congressman Greenwood, 1999 May (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Current events, 1997 May-1999 November (Box 3, Folder 166 - 168)
    - Bernstein, Jill, 1999 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Somers, Anne: Chamber of Commerce, 1999 May (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Somers, Anne: American Society on Aging Senior Award, 1999 March (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - McGinnis, Michael, 1997 March (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1990 October 3 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Lavizzo-Mourey, Risa, 1990 June-1994 (Box 3, Folder 174 - 175)
    - Advisory Committee on Health Promotion, 1990 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - University of Pennsylvania: Alumni/Faculty Exchange, 1990 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Armstrong, Paul, and Alan Hunt, 1990 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Blue Cross, 1990 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - New Jersey Public Health Association, 1989 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Long Term Care financial considerations, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Continuing care retirement communities general, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Pennswood Valley Health Care Reform Committee, 1996 May (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1995 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Freedom from Fear: Victory over Violence Against the Elderly forum, 1992 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Medicare History Project: National Academy of Social Insurance, 1995 January (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Continuing Care Retirement Community book contracts, promotion, and reviews, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Life Care at Home Advisory Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - INSURE Project: Industrywide Network for Social, Urban and Rural Efforts, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Japanese health care, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - International health care, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Evaluation of Consumer Health Education, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Congresswoman Patricia Bauman, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - Prospective Medicine: Health Hazard Appraisal, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Health Systems Agency, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Hospital Community Health Project, Bucks County, Penn., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - Ralston-Penn Center, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - White House Conference on Aging, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - Pride Institute Journal, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - Courier Times, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - Managed Care: Preparing for the Challenges and Opportunities symposium, 1995 September (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - American Association of Retired Persons, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - Job vacancies, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - Physician's Role in Patient Education, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - Nigerian Society for the Advancement of Knowledge and Understanding, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - Kaiser Health Promotion Program, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - Legislative proposals, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - National Institutes of Health, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - Occupational Health, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Hospitals, general, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - School health education, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - Self help/self care, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 212)
    - Diabetes, 1975-1991 (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - Take Care of Yourself: A Consumer's Guide to Medicine by Dr. Donald Vickery, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Urinary incontinence, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - U.S. Preventative Services Task Force, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - Preventative medicine and primary care, 1974-1986 (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - Rural health, circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - Office of Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Periodic exams and screening, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Lifetime Health Monitoring Program, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Nursing associations, 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Strokes, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Interview in Family &Community Health, 1988 November (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Frist, Bill, 2001 June 13 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Somers, Anne, list of publications, 1943-1993 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Aging, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Somers, Anne, awards, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 228)
      - Oversize, 1962-2006 (Box 6, Folder 297)
    - Group photograph including Herman Somers, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Medicare and Social Security, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Pharmaceutical industry, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Reinhardt, Uwe, 1994-2003 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Singer, Peter T., 1998 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - National health insurance, Somers Plan, 1970-1993 (Box 4, Folder 234 - 236)
    - Nursing homes and institutional ethics committees, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - Third Quadrangle Health Issues conference, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - Healthcare Hall of Fame, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - Princeton University Task Force, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - League of Women Voters, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - Rationing Healthcare workshop, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - College of Physicians of Philadelphia, 1976-1994 (Box 4, Folder 245)